[When watching Gin Tama, please keep the lights on and don't sit too close to the TV!]
[He lost his head once and followed his bliss. Then he was fired and his wife ran out on him.]
[Dumb Old Retarded Kook Hasegawa.  Another day of sunbathing at the park.]
[Oedo Children's Park]
(子供のはしゃぎ声)
(神楽)おじちゃん｡
Hey, Pops!
(長谷川)なんだい？
What, little Odd Jobs girl?
万事屋のお嬢ちゃん｡
(神楽)おじちゃんは どうして
いつも昼間から➡
Why are you always here in the middle of the day?
こんなところにいるの？
う～ん…｡
…それはね
仕事 ｸﾋﾞになっちゃったからだよ｡
Well...
Because I was fired from work.
ふ～ん｡
おじちゃんは どうして
仕事 ｸﾋﾞになっちゃったの？
Why were you fired?
う～ん それはね…｡
Well... Because...
一時のﾃﾝｼｮﾝに
身を任せたからだよ｡
It's because I lost my head once and just followed my bliss.
お嬢ちゃんも 若いからって➡
A young girl like you should always think about the consequences of your actions.
後先 考えずに
行動しちゃいけないよ｡
人生ってのは 長いんだから｡
Life is long, you know.
ｵﾒｴに言われたくねえよ 負け組が｡
I don't want to hear that from a loser like you.
See ya, you Dumb Old Retarded Kook! Or "DORK" for short!
じゃあな まるでﾀﾞﾒな おっさん｡
略して ﾏﾀﾞｵ｡
Let's go, Sadaharu.
(神楽)いくよ 定春｡
ﾌｯ… ったく 最近のｶﾞｷは｡
Well...Kids these days are really...
あれ おかしいな…
前がかすんで 見えないや｡
Huh? How strange... Everything got misty and I can't see.
["If You Stop and Think About It, Your Life's a Lot Longer as an Old Guy than a Kid! Whoa, Scary!"]
((じゃあな まるでﾀﾞﾒな おっさん｡
See ya, you Dumb Old Retarded Kook! Or "DORK" for short!
略して ﾏﾀﾞｵ))
《ﾏﾀﾞｵ… 今のｵﾚには
お似合いの言葉だ》
"DORK"... that name fits me well.
To think until just a little while ago I was on the path to great success.
《長谷川:ちょっと前までは
出世街道を ばく進してたのに…》
If only I hadn't made that one error...
《長谷川:もののはずみで
あんなことしちまって…｡
次の日には 御上に呼び出され…》
The next day, I was summoned by my boss.
((上司:腹 切れ｡
ﾏｼﾞっすか!?))
Cut your guts out.
Seriously?!
《長谷川:問答無用で
切腹 申しつけられた｡
He ordered me to commit seppuku.
怖いから
夜逃げしようとしたら…》
I got scared, so I was going skip town...
((んっ!?))
But my wife left me first.
《長谷川:女房が
先に逃げていた》
I can't stand by a DORKH (Dumb Old Retarded Kook Husband) like you anymore. Hatsu.
《長谷川:本当に 何もかも
なくしちまった｡
I lost everything. The only thing I had left were these black sunglasses.
もう ｵﾚには ｸﾞﾗｻﾝくらいしか
残ってねえ…｡
いや いろんなﾓﾝ 失ったかわりに
手に入れたﾓﾝもある》
Well...I lost everything, but I gained something else in return.
(銀時)よう｡
Yo!
Back again, huh? Well, have you racked up the pachinko balls today?
(銀時)また来てたのか｡
どうよ 今日は出てるか？
《長谷川:そう 妙な連れだ》
A strange guy I've fallen in with.
しかし あれだな…｡
By the way,
a guy your age, killing time at this place every day...
ｱﾝﾀも いい歳して
毎日 こんなところで➡
時間つぶしてるたぁ
ｶｯﾌﾟ焼きそばのﾌﾀに付いた➡
It's sad to say, but you're like one of those vegetables that stick to the lid of the cup of chow mein.
野菜なみに 切ねえな｡
What about you?
お前さんこそ その歳で
いつも 真っ昼間から➡
Why is a young guy like you always coming here during the day?
こんなところ
入り浸ってて いいのかよ｡
When your blood sugar level drops, you don't know what to do.
人間 思うように
糖分がとれねえと➡
どうしていいか
わかんなくなるのよ｡
そういうときは こうして➡
So, when that happens, watching small balls popping around like this makes me feel better.
小せえ 玉っころが
はじけてるのを見てると➡
落ち着くんだよな｡
《長谷川:類は友を呼ぶとは
よくいうが➡
It's said that birds of a feather...
ｺｲﾂとは 似た雰囲気を感じた…｡
I felt that he was a fellow human being... It's like...he didn't have any guarantee of living and...
生活に 保障なさげなとことか》
おっ 今日は必勝の予感！
(ﾊﾟﾁﾝｺの当たり音)
Oh! I feel like I'll win today.
あん？ もういくのか？
Oh? You're leaving already?
実は これから
新しい仕事の面接なんだ｡
Actually, I'm going to a job interview.
あら 地道なこと やってんだ｡
Oh? I didn't know you were making a serious effort.
(長谷川)まあな… じゃ｡
Kind of. See ya.
あれ ﾁｬﾝｽ終わった？
Oh? Is my luck already over?
That's right. I need something new, anyway.
《長谷川:そうだ…
とにかく 今のｵﾚは➡
新しいものを
手に入れなくちゃいけねえ｡
ﾏﾀﾞｵは ﾏﾀﾞｵでも➡
I know I'm a DORK, but I should at least become a better man.
まぁ なんとか だらしなくない男
程度には ならないとな…》
[Shuei Commercial Company]
[Mid-Career Employment Opportunities]
[Interview site]
♪♪～
Um...
あの…｡
(章二)ひえぇえっ！
Hey! Stop surprising me, Pops!
なんだよ
ﾋﾞｯｸﾘさせんなよ おっさん！
いや… ﾋﾞｯｸﾘしたの
こっちなんですけど｡
Well...You surprised me.
あの… よかったら
火 使います？
Um... You need a light?
Ah... Thanks.
(章二)あ あぁ… すまねえな｡
なんだか 緊張しちゃってよ…｡
I'm really wound up.
It's upside down. You're too nervous!
逆だから！
緊張しすぎだから ｱﾝﾀ！
悪ぃ 悪ぃ｡ こんなところ来んの
初めてでよ｡
Sorry, sorry. This is the first time I've been to a place like this.
今まで ずっと女に
食わせてもらってたんだが…｡
Huh?
My woman has been providing for me... But now she's pregnant...
その女に ｶﾞｷができてね｡
(章二)近々 産まれるんだよ｡
...and pretty soon...she's going to have a baby.
そこでよ ｵﾚも男らしく…｡
So, I thought I should become a real man.
ちゃんとした職に
つこうと思ってな｡
And I should get...a real job!
H-Hey! It's burning! It's burning!
おいおい 燃えてる 燃えてる！
Oh, yeah! A flame of responsibility is flaring up deep in my heart!
おぅ 責任感っつう炎が➡
ｵﾚの胸の奥で 燃えたぎってるぜ！
No, no! Your head is burning!
そうじゃねえ！ ｱﾝﾀの頭が
燃えたぎってんだよ！
あん？ あっ…｡
うわぁ～っ！
えっ えっ えらいこっちゃ～！
Oh, my god!
What should I do? Water! Water! Water!
どうしよ どうしよ！ 水 水 水！
(係員)遠藤 章二さん｡
Shoji Endo-san, it's time for your interview.
面接 始めます… って 火事かい！
Is that fireworks?!
My wife is taking care of the housework! From now on, I'll earn money for my family!
家事は 嫁がやってくれます！
これからは ｵﾚが
家族のために稼ぎます！
Not that kind of works!
(係員)って その家事じゃねえ～！
H-Hey!
おっ おい…｡
Compared to him, my responsibilities, as a DORK, are so small.
《ｱｲﾂに比べりゃ ﾏﾀﾞｵのｵﾚの
責任感なんざ 小さいもんだ…》
I'm Taizo Hasegawa. It's good to meet you.
長谷川 泰三です｡
よろしくお願いします｡
(大西)先輩…？
ん？
...Senpai...?
Oh?
長谷川先輩じゃねえすか！
Hasegawa Senpai, is that you?!
お前は 入国管理局を辞めた…｡
You...quit the Department of Immigration Control?
I'm Onishi!
大西っす！ いやあ
こんなところで 会えるとは…｡
Oh, my! I never thought I'd see you in a place like this! What are you doing here?
どうしたんすか 今日は また｡
ｵﾚも いろいろあってね…｡
I've had a lot of problems.
そうか そうか…
お前がいる会社なら ｵﾚも安心だ｡
But I'm glad to know you're working for this company.
昔のよしみで ちょっと上に
口 きいてくんないか？ なぁ…｡
I wonder if you can put in a good word for me with your boss for old time's sake.
ふざけんじゃねえよ！
Are you kidding?!
あ… あれ？ 大西君？
Um...Oh? Onishi-kun?
ﾃﾒｴ 長谷川…｡
You, Hasegawa!
(大西)入国管理局のときは
ずいぶん世話になったなぁ…｡
Thanks for everything you did for me while I was working at the Department of Immigration Control!
いや… ｵﾚも あんときは
上からの命令で しかたなく…｡
Well, I didn't have any choice, at the time, because of my boss.
Shut up! If you want to work here, get on your knees and shave off that goatee, baldy!
うるせえっ！
ここで仕事したかったら➡
まずは ｵﾚにひざまずいて
そのﾋｹﾞ 取れや ﾊｹﾞ！
ぐえぇっ… ﾋｹﾞっすか!?
My goatee?
No complaining! And take off those sunglasses!
文句あんのかぁ？
この際 ｸﾞﾗｻﾝも取れ ｺﾞﾗｧ！
いや… ｸﾞﾗｻﾝだけは！
No, please...my sunglasses...
You don't have a job, but you do have some hang-ups, huh?!
職はねえくせに
こだわりだけは あるってか！
ｱﾝﾀ あれだ… ﾏｼﾞでださい ｵﾔｼﾞ
略してﾏﾀﾞｵだな！
You know what, you're a Dumb Old Retarded Kooky Geek, a DORKG!
(大西の叫び声)
《とにかく それからは
最悪だった》
Anyway, everything has been going wrong since then.
Can you do something about your hairstyle and sunglasses?
((面接官:その髪型とｸﾞﾗｻﾝ
どうにかしてくんないかな？
(面接官)それだと まさに
だるそうな おじさん➡
They make you look like a DORK! A Drowsy Old Retarded Kook.
略して ﾏﾀﾞｵだよ？
(面接官)お口のにおいと
ｸﾞﾗｻﾝが ちょっとね…｡
Your bad breath and sunglasses are a problem. You're a...
ｱﾝﾀ まったく 堕落しちまった
おっさん… 略してﾏﾀﾞｵだね！))
DORK, a Degraded Old Retarded Kook.
《長谷川:どこへ行っても
ﾏﾀﾞｵ ﾏﾀﾞｵ…》
No matter where I go, I'm called DORK.
(そばをすする音)
Hey, Master! This soup and fried tofu tastes really awful!
(客)おいっ ｵﾔｼﾞ！ なんだよ
このまずい ﾀﾞｼとお揚げ！
略して ﾏﾀﾞｵじゃねえか！
In short, it's DORKS! A Disgusting Overcooked Rotten Kefir flavored Stock.
Shut up!
(長谷川)うるせ～!!
ﾏﾀﾞｵだったら どうだってんだ！
What's wrong with being a DORK?!
《長谷川:こういうときは
酒にかぎる…》
There's nothing like sake to help me relax.
You know, I'm having chest pains around here these days...
(ﾑｰさん)もうね… なんか最近➡
胸の このあたりが
ｽﾞｷｽﾞｷ痛くてさ…｡
恋わずらいかな…｡
I wonder if this is a love sickness.
You should go see a doctor, Mu-san.
(お登勢)それ 病院
行ったほうがいいよ ﾑｰさん｡
(お登勢)気ぃつけて帰んなよ｡
Get home safely.
Oh, welcome.
(お登勢)あら いらっしゃい｡
(長谷川)う～ん…｡
Hey, you! I'm closing.
ｱﾝﾀ ちょっと もう 店 閉めるよ｡
もうちっとくらい
飲ませてくれてもいいじゃんかよ｡
Huh? Can't you let me stay a bit longer for another cup of sake?
(長谷川)胸につかえた
つらい現実を➡
I'm trying to get rid of harsh realities, that weigh heavily on my stomach, with sake.
酒で とっちまいてえんだよ…｡
Well, I hope you don't throw up the food you just ate,
っていうか 胸につかえてる
さっき食ったﾓﾝを➡
which weighs heavy on your stomach, on the bar counter.
ｶｳﾝﾀｰに ぶちまけないでくれよ｡
(お登勢)ほら ｻﾝｸﾞﾗｽ取って
目ぇ覚ましな｡
Hey, take off your sunglasses and wake up.
うるせえなぁ｡ ｵﾚは 大丈夫だよ｡
Leave me alone. I'm fine.
なに 言ってんのさ｡
What are you talking about?
You're a Drunk Old Recovering Knocked Down Customer.
ｱﾝﾀ まったく
大丈夫じゃないお客｡
...in short, a DORKC.
(お登勢)略して ﾏﾀﾞｵだよ｡
Keh. Whatever... DORKC... What the hell?!
《ｹｯ｡ なにがﾏﾀﾞｵだ｡ ﾁｸｼｮｳ》
Hey, brother! I have the perfect bar for you.
(客引き)おにいさん
いい店 ありますよ｡
《こうなったら 勢いしかねえ》
Well, why not?
[Snack SMILE]
Nice to meet you. I'm Otae.
(お妙)はじめまして｡ お妙です｡
なんか ここ
高そうなお店だけどさ➡
This looks like a really expensive place. But I don't have much money.
ｵﾚ 今 あんまり金ないよ｡
そうですか｡ わかりました｡
Is that so? I understand.
すみませ～ん ﾄﾞﾝﾍﾟﾘひとつ｡
Excuse me! One Dom Pérignon!
She didn't get it! This lady doesn't understand Japanese!
通じてないよ この人！
日本語 全然 通じてないよ！
Is this the International Pub?
ここ 多国籍ﾊﾟﾌﾞ？
Sir...
お客さん 腕時計と指輪と
ｻﾝｸﾞﾗｽも高そうだし➡
Your watch, ring and sunglasses look expensive, so why don't you sell them?
売っ払ってきちゃえば？
ｸﾞﾗｻﾝは やめて！
No, not my sunglasses! Is this a highway robbery pub?
ここ おいはぎﾊﾟﾌﾞですか!?
You're still being stubborn.
この期に及んで
往生際が悪いのは➡
You're a Diehard Older Rigid Kind of Man. In short, a DORKM, sir.
まともに抱かれたくない男…➡
略して ﾏﾀﾞｵですよ お客さん｡
Hold on!
(近藤)ちょっと待った～!!
ということは なんですか!?
Are you trying to say, if I weren't so stubborn,
往生際さえよければ
お妙さんの ﾏｼﾞで抱かれたい男➡
I would become a Desirable Older Respectful Kind-hearted Man? A DORKM?!
略して… ﾏﾀﾞ…！
何にします？ お客さん｡
What would you like to order, sir?
…ﾄﾞﾝﾍﾟﾘ ひとつください｡
One Dom Péri, please.
Thank you very much!
(ﾎﾞｰｲ)ありがとうございました～｡
はぁ～あ…｡
あ～あ もう夜明けだよ…｡
Man, it's almost dawn.
Hey, you...wait a minute.
(桂)おぬし ちょっと待て｡
What? Why would a monk need me?
なんだ？ 坊さんが なんの用だよ｡
坊さんじゃない｡ 桂だ｡
I'm not a monk.
I'm Katsura.
突然だが おぬし
このｵﾚとともに 剣を取り➡
I know this is sudden, but...
Are you interested in taking up a sword and venturing out for the dawning of Japan?
日本の夜明けへと
賭けてみないか！
What are you trying to say this early in the morning?
ｱﾝﾀ 朝っぱらから
なに言ってやがる…｡
(爆発音と悲鳴)
(土方)桂!!
ﾃﾒｴ 今日こそ観念しやがれ！
Katsura! Be prepared to lose today!
Tsk! The Shinsengumi!
ﾁｯ 真選組か！
ここは 一度 退くぞ！
どういうことだよ おにいさん！
Let's retreat for now.
Hey! What's going on, brother?
おにいさんじゃない！ 桂だ!!
I'm not your brother! I'm Katsura!
All right. I know, already!
(長谷川)わかった！
それは わかったからさ…！
いででで…｡
The game is about over, bomber!
(土方)年貢の納めどきだ 爆弾魔！
もう… やだ｡
Whatever.
(土方)いいかげん 白状しやがれ!!
Come on! Why don't you confess?!
だから ｵﾚは 何も関係ないって！
I already said that I have nothing to do with it.
(土方)わかったって｡ いいから➡
I understand. So just tell us where Katsura is hiding.
桂の潜んでるところだけでも
吐いちまえよ｡
You really don't understand what I said!
全然 わかってねえよ それ！
(沖田)ｱﾝﾀさ～
身元も はっきりしねえのに➡
You know, you don't have any identification and you keep insisting that you're not involved.
関係ないの一点張りじゃあ
疑わねえほうが ﾑﾘもあるだろう｡
Because of that, we can't help but suspect you.
だから ｵﾚは 元入国管理局の
長谷川ってもんだ｡
I'm telling you, I'm Hasegawa, and I used to work at the Department of Immigration Control.
調べればわかる！
You'd know if you checked!
If you are going to lie, at least make it believable.
つくのなら もうちっと
ﾏｼなｳｿ つきやがれ｡
いや だから ﾎﾝﾄなんだってば！
No, it's true, already!
じゃあ 身ぐるみ剥いで
調べさせてもらおっか｡
Then we'll strip you and check!
ｸﾞﾗｻﾝ取れ ｸﾞﾗｻﾝ！
Take off your sunglasses. Your sunglasses!
Hold on a minute! Not my sunglasses!
ちょっと待って!! ｸﾞﾗｻﾝはやめて！
Hopefully not my clothes, either! Believe me, I used to work at the Department of Immigration Control!
できれば 服も…｡ つうか➡
ﾎﾝﾄに 入国管理局で
働いてたんだってば！
ｱﾝﾀさ～ まったく だませない
おとぼけ｡
You know, you're a Deceiving Overprotected Red-handed Kook, in short, DORK.
略して ﾏﾀﾞｵだ｡
Take your clothes off, now!
[Investigation room]
(土方)とっとと脱げ ほら！
After all, I'm a DORK no matter where I go.
No, not those!
《長谷川:結局 ｵﾚは
どこへ行ってもﾏﾀﾞｵだった…》
Give up, old man!
(土方)二度と 来るんじゃねえぞ！
Don't come back!
I guess we got up early this morning for nothing.
(沖田)今日 早起きして
損しましたね｡
So true.
(土方)まったくだ｡
The only thing I had left were these sunglasses.
《もう ｵﾚに残っているのは
ｸﾞﾗｻﾝだけだ…》
ｺﾗ！
少しは 言うこと聞きやがれって！
Hey! You'd better listen to me!
おう なにやってんだ？
こんなところで｡
Hey, what are you doing here?
そうか… また 面接ﾀﾞﾒだったのか｡
I see. Your interview didn't go well again.
(長谷川)あぁ 全滅さ｡
Right, they totally shot me down.
(長谷川)それどころか 変な連中に
やたら からまれてな…｡
In fact, I was tangled up with so many strange guys...
どいつもｺｲﾂも ﾏﾀﾞｵだの
ｸﾞﾗｻﾝ取れだのって言いやがって｡
Every one of them called me a DORK and wanted me to take off my sunglasses.
ｸﾞﾗｻﾝは 顔の一部だぜ｡
取れるわけねえじゃねえか｡
These sunglasses are a part of my face.
There's no way I can take them off.
Dumbass! Stop blaming everything on your sunglasses!
ﾊﾞｶ野郎！ なんでも
ｸﾞﾗｻﾝのせいにしてんじゃねえよ!!
つまづき転んだのを
石のせいにしたところで➡
Do you blame a rock when you trip over it? Does it change anything?
何か変わるか！
(ｵﾔｼﾞ)いや…➡
Well, all you need to do is take off your sunglasses.
ｸﾞﾗｻﾝ取れば いい話だろ｡
Heh... You're saying it's because of my sunglasses that I can't change myself?
ﾍｯ… ｸﾞﾗｻﾝではなく
ｵﾚに変われと？
この歳で 今さらｵﾚが
変われると思ってんのかよ｡
You think I can change myself at this age?
もういい 座れよ｡
That's enough. Sit down.
おい ｵﾔｼﾞ｡ ｺｲﾂに➡
Hey, Master. Give him something that reminds him of his mother's cooking.
おふくろの味的なものを…｡
いや わかんねえよ｡
Now how the hell do I do that?
[Oden]
おふくろの味っつったら おめっ➡
Speaking of his mother's cooking, there's nothing better than Digestive Biscuits!
ﾀﾞｲｼﾞｪｽﾃｨﾌﾞﾋﾞｽｹｯﾄに
決まってんだろうが！
What kind of mother are you talking about?!
(ｵﾔｼﾞ)どんな母ちゃんだよ！
Hasegawa-san, It's okay to have a code of honor...and live by it...
長谷川さんよ…➡
信念もって
まっすぐ生きるのも 結構だがよ➡
ｿｲﾂのせいで
身動きとれなくなるくらいなら➡
But if you can't get anywhere because of it,
いっぺん 曲がってみるってのも
手なんじゃねえの？
it might not be a bad idea to reverse course.
ｸﾞﾆｬｸﾞﾆｬ 曲がりくねってても
いいじゃねえか｡
Why not break all the rules?
そうしてるうちに➡
Along the way, there'll come a point when you finally find something that matters to you
絶対 譲れねえ
１本の芯みてえなもんも➡
見えてくんじゃねえか？
more than your code, right?
ｸﾞﾗｻﾝにこだわるのは
それからでも遅くねえよ｡
After that, you can wear your sunglasses as much as you want.
《長谷川:そして ｵﾚは…》
And I...
♪♪～
長谷川 泰三です｡
よろしくお願いしま～す！
I'm Taizo Hasegawa. Nice to meet you.
《長谷川:とうとう ｵﾚは
ｸﾞﾗｻﾝも失った…》
I've finally taken off my sunglasses.
What kind of work did you do before, Hasegawa-san?
(面接官)長谷川さんは
以前 どんな仕事を？
I was fighting against evil aliens to save Earth.
地球を守るため
悪い宇宙人と戦ってました｡
(面接官)ｱｯﾊｯﾊｯﾊｯﾊ！
おもしろいね｡ 採用！
You're so funny.
We'll hire you.
《長谷川:ｸﾞﾗｻﾝひとつ取っただけで
こうも 人生が変わるとは…｡
I didn't realize that just taking off my sunglasses could make this much difference in my life.
I hate doing what young people tell me to, but now I think it has nothing to do with age.
若造の言いなりになるのは
しゃくだったが➡
人間ってのは
年齢うんぬんじゃねえ｡
ｵﾚより 短い人生で➡
Even people who haven't lived as long as me know more about life.
ずっと 多くのことを感じて
生きている若造も➡
いるってことだ…》
(長谷川)お客さん どちらまで？
Sir, where to?
Don't call him sir! Call him President!
(軍曹)お客さんじゃない！
隊長と お呼びしろ！
はい？
Huh?
Cut it out, guys! Sorry, Driver. Please take us to the Cultural Center.
(新八)やめろ お前ら｡
運転手さん すまない｡
文化ｾﾝﾀｰまで頼むわ｡
はい 隊長…｡
All right, President.
Hurry up! Otsu-chan's live show is about to start!
(軍曹)早くしろよ！
お通ちゃんのﾗｲﾌﾞ➡
始まっちゃうだろ！
(長谷川)は はい… 隊長！
All right, President.
I'm not a President! I'm a sergeant!
(軍曹)隊長じゃない！
ｵﾚは 軍曹だ!!
《人を運ぶ仕事やってると
つくづく思う…｡
Through my work as a driver...I realize how great it is to have a destination.
目的地があるってのは
いいもんだ》
ｴｽﾃ 黄泉返りまで｡
The "Back From the Dead" salon.
I had so many customers. And everyone had a clear vision.
《長谷川:いろんな客を乗せたが➡
To the hospital.
どいつもｺｲﾂも
目に 濁りがねえ｡》
To Kabukicho.
かぶき町まで｡
《長谷川:確かに
人生は変わったが…》
My life has sure changed... But I no longer have a destination.
Drive until I see the dawn of a new Japan.
日本の夜明けまで｡
《長谷川:おっさんは
目的地を見失っちまった》
You see the skuzzy-looking guy smoking over there? Run him over, but try not to kill him.
あそこで ﾀﾊﾞｺ吸ってる
ふてぶてしい男がいるだろ？
あれ 死なない程度に はねてくれ｡
《長谷川:おっさんは
これから どうなるのだろう？
What should an old fellow like me do?
おっさんは これから
どこへ行くのだろう？
I wonder where I should go?
まるで おっさんは ひとりだけ
目的地の見えない迷子だ｡
I feel like a child who has no destination.
I'm... I'm... I'm...!
おっさんは… おっさんは…
おっさんは！》
I don't care where, but take me someplace.
どこでもいいからよ～
乗せてってくれや｡
Then I found someone who is a lost child like me.
《長谷川:いた…
ｵﾚと同じ迷い子が》
暇なんだよ～
ﾀﾀﾞで 連れまわしてくれよ｡
I have nothing to do. Take me around anywhere for free.
Are you kidding me?! I'm on the job.
ふざけんなよ ﾃﾒｴ｡
こっちは 仕事でやってんだよ｡
いいだろ お前｡
地平線の向こう側へ➡
It's okay. I just want to see the other side of the horizon.
行ってみたいんだ｡
(長谷川)ﾃﾒｴは 彼女か！
Who do you think you are...my girlfriend?!
どうよ？ 仕事のほうは｡
How's your job?
ﾃﾒｴが来るまで 順調だったよ｡
It was fine until you got in.
こないだは
死人みてえなﾂﾗしてやがったが➡
You looked like a dead man when I saw you the other day, but you look better now.
ちったぁﾏｼなﾂﾗに
なったじゃねえか｡
Whatever. Nothing has changed.
ほざけよ｡
何も変わっちゃいねえよ｡
I changed my job, but I still don't have a purpose.
(長谷川)仕事 変えたってだけで
目的も何もねえ｡
I don't have a clear vision for my future.
先なんて見えちゃいねえんだよ｡
そんなもんだろ みんな｡
I guess everyone is in the same boat.
地べた はいずりながら
探してりゃ そのうち見つかるさ｡
If you keep seeking it, you'll find it eventually.
I don't think so.
いや 違うような気がする｡
Because, in this show, you and I are the only ones with cloudy looking eyes.
だって このｱﾆﾒで 目が濁ってんの
ｵﾚと お前だけだもん｡
(長谷川)…あぁ 客だ｡
もう お前 降りろ この野郎｡
Oh, here comes a customer. Get out of my car, jackass!
(２人)ん？
Why is he here?! What is he doing here?!
なんで ｱｲﾂがいんだ？
なんで ｱｲﾂがいんだ!?
Start the car now! I don't want to get in trouble!
車 出せ！ 早く！
面倒事は ごめんだぜ！
Take me to Ueno Zoo. And make it snappy, please.
(ﾊﾀ皇子)上野動物園まで頼むぞ｡
急いでくりゃれ｡
Oh? Haven't I seen you two somewhere before?
…ん？ おぬしら２人
どこぞで会ったかのぅ？
知りませんよ｡
誰ですか？ あなた｡
I don't know. Who are you?
頭に 卑猥なもの付けちゃって｡
You have something nasty on your head.
Earthlings, um, all look like they've been sucking on lemons.
地球人なんて みんな
醤油顔ですからね～ みんな｡
Oh I see. Fair enough.
(ﾊﾀ)そうか｡
それならいいんじゃが｡
じゃあ 長谷川さん
ﾎﾞｸ そろばん塾あるんで｡
So, Hasegawa-san, I have to go to abacus class now. Have a nice day!
お疲れ～っす｡
Wait!
待て！ ひとりにしないでくれ！
Don't leave me alone! I'm begging you!
Don't leave this old fellow all alone! I'm old! If I get too lonely I'll die!
おっさんをひとりにしないでくれ
おっさんはな➡
寂しいと死んじゃうんだ!!
ﾊﾑｽﾀｰか ﾃﾒｴは！
What are you... a hamster or something?!
Hey, start the car!
(ﾊﾀ)おい 早く出せ ｺﾗ｡
(長谷川)は はい すんません｡
Y-Yes. I'm sorry.
(長谷川)幸い ﾔﾂは
ｵﾚたちに気づいてねえ｡
Luckily, it appears he doesn't remember me.
ﾊﾟｰｯと送って ﾊﾟｰｯと帰りゃ
ﾊﾞﾚねえよ｡
Let's take him there quickly and leave before he does remember. Then we'll be safe.
Then release me now.
だったら ｵﾚを解放してくれ｡
ﾔﾀﾞ｡ ｺﾜｲ｡ ｻﾋﾞｼｲ｡
No, sir, uh-huh! Me scared...and lonely!
Why are you speaking like a foreigner now?!
なんで そこだけ外人なんだよ!?
I can't believe he had his driver's license suspended.
まったく じいのﾔﾂめ
いい歳こいて 免停とは…｡
何故 皇子たる余が➡
Why do I, a prince, have to take a dirty taxi?
こんな汚えﾀｸｼｰ
使わねばならんのだ｡
(ﾊﾀ)のぅ そこの銀髪
手が空いてるなら 余に ｻｰﾋﾞｽせい｡
Hey, silver-haired man! If you have nothing to do, give me some service.
Well... I said service, but why are you washing my hair?
いや ｻｰﾋﾞｽだけれども…
なんで よりによって洗髪？
社長さん 地球へは何しに？
Mr. President, what brought you to Earth?
I'm not a president. What are you talking about?!
(ﾊﾀ)社長じゃねえよ！
なんなんだ お前は｡
あれだ あれ
急に ﾊﾟﾝﾀﾞが見たくなって…｡
You know, I just wanted to see a panda all of a sudden. Ow! Ow!
いっ！ ｲﾀﾀ!! 目に入ってるって！
I've got shampoo in my eyes! You did that on purpose, didn't you?!
つうか お前
わざとやってんだろ!!
I see... You've come to see a panda, Mr. President.
あぁ ﾊﾟﾝﾀﾞなんか見にきたの？
社長さん｡
だまされちゃいけないよ～｡
But don't be fooled.
It's said that they eat only bamboo, but we never know what they really eat.
ﾔﾂら 笹しか食わねえとか
謳ってるけどさぁ➡
実際 裏じゃ 何 食ってるか
知れたもんじゃねえよ｡
They may even eat Shabu-Shabu.
しゃぶしゃぶとか
食ってっかもよ｡
ん…？ うわぁ～っ!!
(急ﾌﾞﾚｰｷ音)
I-I-I-I-Idiot! Are you trying to get yourself killed?! What were you thinking?!
ﾊﾞﾊﾞﾊﾞﾊﾞﾊﾞ ﾊﾞｶ野郎！
危ねえだろ！ なに考えてんだ!!
ん？ ﾃﾒｴは 面接のときの…｡
I saw you at my job interview.
Oh, Pops! This is an emergency.
Please give us a ride!
おっさん！ 頼む 急用なんだ｡
乗せてくれ！
(長谷川)苦しい… やめろ…！
Ugh! I can't breathe! Stop!
Sachiko... my Sachiko has suddenly gone into labor!
さち子が… さち子が
急に 産気づいちまって！
My goodness! My charm point has been pulled off!
ぎゃあ～っ！
余のﾁｬｰﾑﾎﾟｲﾝﾄが取れてしまった!!
やべ… 急に止まるから
取れちまったじゃねえか｡
Oops! Because the car stopped suddenly, it accidentally fell off.
どうしてくれるんじゃ ｷｻﾏ～!!
What are you going to do about this?!
Without this, I look like a human. Like an assistant manager!
それがなかったら 余は
ただの人間じゃん！ 係長じゃん｡
Don't worry. You look at least manager level.
大丈夫ですって｡
課長ｸﾗｽには見えますよ｡
That's not my point!
(ﾊﾀ)
そういう問題じゃねえんだよ！
だいたい 取れるってことは
いらねえってことなんですよ｡
You know what? It fell off so easily,
so it must mean you don't need it.
Hey, you two!
(長谷川)ちょっ いいかい
お二人さん｡
今にも ｶﾞｷが産まれそうな
女がいんだ｡
There's a woman who's gone into labor!
銀さん
この辺に 産婦人科あるか？
Gin-san, is there a maternity clinic nearby?
ねえよ 戻らねえと｡
Nope. You'll have to turn back.
Tsk. Then we should go back.
ﾁｯ… じゃあ すぐ戻んねえと｡
Are you kidding?!
ふざけるなぁ～！
I lose my charm point and now I have to go back? Give me a break!
ﾁｬｰﾑﾎﾟｲﾝﾄが もがれたうえ
引き返すだと!? ﾅﾒてんのか!?
All right, the least you can do is take me to the damn panda!
こうなったら
意地でも ﾊﾟﾝﾀﾞを見るぞ！
(ﾊﾀ)早く 車 出せ！ ｺﾗ!!
Now get moving!
Can't you direct a tiny fraction of your love for pandas towards human beings?
ｱﾝﾀよぉ ﾊﾟﾝﾀﾞの ひとかけらでも➡
地球人に
愛情 向けられねえのかい？
A human baby-that's real cute, too, you know.
人間の赤ん坊も
そりゃ かわいいもんですぜ｡
Who cares? Who gets cuddly feelings about uppity, hairless monkeys?!
知るかぁ！ ｷｻﾏのような➡
下等で ﾅﾏｲｷな猿に
情などわくか!!
(ﾊﾀ)地球人のｶﾞｷが
１人や２人 どうなろうと➡
I really don't care what happens to one or two human babies!
知ったことではない！
余を誰だと思ってんじゃ!!
Who do you think I am?! I'm... I'm...
余はなぁ… ﾌｺﾞｯ！
Who are you?! You're just some assistant manager, right?
誰なんだよ？
ただの係長だろうがよ｡
(長谷川)やめねえか…｡
Cut it out. What do you think you're doing to the Prince?
皇子様に なんてﾏﾈすんだ ﾃﾒｴは｡
(長谷川)わかりました 皇子様｡
I understand, Prince.
要は ﾊﾟﾝﾀﾞ見れれば
いいんですよね？
You'll be happy if you see a panda, right?
意外と 近場に ﾊﾟﾝﾀﾞがいることに
気づきましたよ｡
I just remembered there's a panda nearby, actually.
ﾎﾝﾄか？ どこだ？
What? Really? Where?
Just look at your face in the mirror tomorrow!
明日 鏡で 自分の顔 見てみろ!!
ぶはぁっ!!
べちょ！
Hey, you hoodlum couple! My cab's suddenly empty. You need a ride?
(長谷川)おい ﾁﾝﾋﾟﾗ夫婦
ちょうど 席 空いたぞ｡ 乗るか？
おっさ～ん 恩にきるぜ!!
Pops! I owe you one!
ﾌｯ｡
Hasegawa-san, just as I thought...
長谷川さんよぉ
ｱﾝﾀ やっぱり あれだな…➡
ｸﾞﾗｻﾝのほうが似合ってんな｡
...you look much better with your sunglasses on.
(長谷川)そうだろ？
I know that.
[Oedo Children's Park]
おじちゃ～ん｡
Hey, old man!
I haven't seen you in a while. Why did you come back here?
しばらく見かけなかったのに
なんで また戻ってきたの？
ん～？ それはねぇ➡
Because I was fired again.
また 仕事
ｸﾋﾞになっちゃったからだよ｡
Why were you fired?
なんで ｸﾋﾞになっちゃったの？
Oh? Because...
(長谷川)ん～？ それはねぇ➡
自分の芯を通したからだよ｡
I was true to myself.
でも おじちゃんは
少しも落ち込んでないよ｡
But I'm not really disappointed.
I may be a hard case, but I am what I am. I've decided to live my life the way I want.
不器用なりに ｵﾚは ｵﾚらしく
まっすぐ生きようと決めたからね｡
不器用って言葉 使えば
かっこつくと思ってんじゃねえぞ｡
Don't go thinking you're cool just because you call yourself a "Hard Case," you jobless loser!
無職が｡
行くよ 定春｡
Let's go, Sadaharu.
See ya Delusional Old Reality-ignoring Knocklehead. Or "DORK" for short.
じゃあな まっすぐ生きても
台なしな人生のおっさん｡
略して ﾏﾀﾞｵ｡
I'm starting to feel dissatisfied again.
なんか もう やんなっちゃったな｡
♪♪～
[Preview]
Takasugi, what are you doing here?
I heard there was a festival. So I had to come.
Don't tell me... You bastard...
The next episode:
"Sons Only Take After Their Fathers' Negative Attributes."
["Gengai Hiraga" Brilliant inventor in Edo. His robots are going to perform at the country opening festival.]
[Karakuri Robot "Saburo" playing house with Kagura?]
(ため息)
Get him!
Oh!